<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Notes to Self; thoughts on BJJ techniques</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Notes to Self; thoughts on BJJ techniques</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 09:58:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Guard Retention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardretention/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 09:58:07 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/guardretention/</guid>
      <description>Guard retention: 3 stages, early middle late.&#xA;Framing; cross shoulder (arms) and cross waist (legs) with a C type body position to make rotation easy. I basically sticky myself to my opponent and then no matter how fast/slow they move, I come along for the ride. If I lose the position and their passing is advancing, the mini-granby rolls get used to make space and change the angle for me, basically getting me off the original line my opponent was trying to pass (ie.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emily Kwok Seminar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/emilykwokseminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:13:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/emilykwokseminar/</guid>
      <description>Emily Kwok seminar Aug 24 was interesting. She covered SLX and X-guard, how they interrelate and transitions between the two.&#xA;X-guard: 3 main things you can do from this position; elevation (what people commmonly expect) which is lifting them up, extension which is pushing them away, and third, which she started with, is off-balancing them. The off-balanacing is the most subtle, with two important points. First, I found for it to work, their leg closest to my head (their ankle) really needs to be almost skin to skin with the side of my neck.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Control To Back with Turtle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontroltoback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:14:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontroltoback/</guid>
      <description>Transition from side control gone wrong:&#xA;Starting in side control, when the opponent has made to much space and begun to re-guard, I want to transition and spin to their back. Place hand on back of their head to pull down, so if I miss the leg step over I don’t nail them in the face. I then step over and put my foot behind the mid point of their back, and put it close so it acts as a wedge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Control Offense, Arm Trapping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontroloffense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 11:12:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontroloffense/</guid>
      <description>Beginning in side mount, the idea is how to integrate this position into the previous half guard/mount attack sequencing. Initially looking to pin the nearside arm of the opponent under my shin. They could have their arm in basically in 3 different positions, but the goal is the same.&#xA;If they’re going for the underhook strongly, and I can’t pin the arm, use knee and go for the bicep; it’ll suck for them and you’ll quickly get the arm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Escaping Mount; subs from mount</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/escapemount/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 13:47:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/escapemount/</guid>
      <description>Escaping Mount:&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s an a/b choice. Start with arm across hip, and other arm tucked in tight to body and supporting the other arm. Feet are as close to myself as possible, then bridge hard and shrimp. Depending on their reaction:&#xA;a) if you end up in modified mount, shrimp into the leg that&amp;rsquo;s against my stomach (my instinct of shrimping other way is wrong) and attempt to stretch them out so there&amp;rsquo;s space to get my leg in/under them to create space and knee shield.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Control, and tweaks to back attack/triangle armbar combo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 13:16:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sidecontrol/</guid>
      <description>2 main sections, side control escape and further tweaks to back attack triangle/armbar combo.&#xA;For the back, big difference is getting higher up before I transition from giftwrap to back. Think around the height of their head to put my knee, instead of behind their shoulder blade. Once on the back, can fight for the RNC. If I feel like I need to get higher once I&amp;rsquo;m already on the back, can push down on their shoulder to try and get higher up their back.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additional Back Details, Two Movement Patterns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/movementpatterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/movementpatterns/</guid>
      <description>Covered 3 areas; more details and reps for back finish, and two movement patterns that are likely to occur from escaping side control.&#xA;Back details:&#xA;Biggest one that seems of no consequence but is super important is when going for the armbar from the back, make sure to get my lower leg weaved above opponents arms (i.e. almost under their chin) so that when their grip breaks and they try and posture/hitchhiker/etc I’m already in place and not scrambling to try and get my position set.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
